Vishesh

Call +91-9536029049 | Whatsapp +60-176184750 | v.shesh@outlook.com

IT Professional Developer with Java Spring Boot as Current Technology

Aspiring to work in a value-based project where my skills can be applied and recognized in dynamic technological scenario leading my career towards full stack developer in Cloud Ecosystem. Getting great support from StackOverFlow and providing it back.

PS: Please take your time by using the links in various location in my resume.

Experience Summary

Overall experience	9.5yr of rich IT experience in JAVA Spring Boot – Oracle - Angula	
Designation	Technical Lead at Newt Global Pvt. Ltd. Chennai	

Technical skills

ecilifical skills		
Technologies	Java 8, Spring MVC and Spring Boot, J2EEE, DSA, API, JUnit, Angular, TypeScript, JavaScript, Hibernate, Python, Oracle SQL, JSP, PL/SQL, MySQL, PostgreSQL Ajax, Microservices, jBoss Server, nginx, Soap Services (Restful), Maven, Gradle, Docker, Kubernetes, Apache Active MQ and Kafka, Azure AD, Terraform and Shell Scripting	
Operations	Agile, DevOps	
Operating System	MacOS, Windows, Unix	
Database and Tools	Visual Studio Code, ECLIPSE, Spring Tool Suite, SQL Developer, PGAdmin, Control-M, Movelt, Swagger, Putty, WinSCP, Postman, Soap UI, Kibana web application (Logs check), Stash, JIRA, Github, Gitbash, Bitbucket	
Skills at Project	 Design, develop, test, deploy, maintain, and improve software. Manage individual project priorities, deadlines, and deliverables. Perform peer coding review and discuss on their approach for solution. Design and implement new user-facing features in existing products. Write client-side code for web-based applications, create fast, easy-to-use, high volume production applications, and develop prototypes. Optimize web applications to maximize speed and scale. 	

Certification

- AZ-204 Azure Developer <u>Link</u>
- AZ-400 Azure DevOps Link

Working Experience Summary

orking Experience			
Project#5	N <u>ewt Global</u> (25 ^h Marach,2024-Now)		
Description of project	DMAP is Data Modernization Acceleration Platform Tool. We provide automation tool to customers for Migrating from Oracle DB to Postgres DB in 12/16 weeks window. Clients' intent to migrate to PostgreSQL to save running cost of legacy applications by moving out of Oracle as PostgreSQL is supported by Open Community.		
Inside Project	Technologies: Python 3.19 Docker Podman Jenkins Java 1.7, J2EEE Spring 5 UNIX – bash and ksh Roles and Responsibilities: Core responsibility is to keep improving feedback by the mode of monkey testing it and logging Jira tickets. Collaborate with Client teams to enable them using DMAP tool in Remediating Embedded Oracle SQL to Postgres SQL for smooth migration of application. Utilize DMAP in client projects and provide feedback to core engineering team to enhance tool. Manage team for Java, Shell script and DB related queries. Test the Migrated application and provide fixed if any help required. Work with manager to Prepare SOW. Analyzing all details of client application and project before SOW is signed. Summaries daily task with excel and pivot and publish daily status to client and Newt manager. Create Azure resource group from team and make sure to setup alerts to monitor costing of resources created by team.		
Project#4	<u>Softenger</u> Malaysia Sdn. Bhd. (16 th May,2023 - March,2024)		
Description of project	Client <u>Public Bank</u> eBanking application of Public Bank for Intra and Inter Bank Funds Transfer, checking Fraud Beneficiaries, DuitNow Transfers, Gold Investment. Public Bank needs to apply the Policies and Regulations launched by Bank Negara Malaysia which is the Central Bank of Malaysia. My team consists of Nationals from China, Philippines, Malaysian Tamils.		
Inside Project	Technologies: Java 1.7, J2EEE Spring 5 UNIX HTML templates Ajax Roles and Responsibilities: Understanding the Business and proposing the use cases accordingly.		

- Propose changes to Requestor if some point missed in requirement as per Use case.
- Deliver Changes as per Requirement before deadline.
- To follow coding standards followed by company and suggested by the Project lead in Code Review.
- Assist in UAT and work on UAT comments if any.
- Working with Data Structures to process huge records from file on Unix location. Working with my lead to change in Code Review.
- Set-up a standalone WebSocket application using Spring 5.3.8 to replace existing functionality of Mobile authentication that is done by Long-Polling Method.
- Implemented websocket using javax.websocket and org.springframework.spring-websocket to replace long-polling in POC.
- Understanding the complex application flow to log-out user validating with several criteria.
- Keeping same time stamp in all notifications blasted to Customers,
 Emails, SMS, Push notification for banking Transaction.
- Analyze application logs for troubleshooting.
- Developed Blacklist Phone Number Functionality when user Register,
 Manage or Transfer to Blacklisted number.

Project#3

Newt Global (2nd Dec,2019- 5th May,2023)

Description of project

Client Lumen

Lumen provides Broadband services to US citizens for which it maintains numerous in house developed applications. Projects that we are supporting and developing.

IMPROV Dashboard:

- Development task Angular 11, HTML, CSS
- Interacts with API of Improv 2.0 application using http calls.
- IMPROV 2.0 are bunch of webservices hosted by Lumen in its internal server for many clients to be consumed with No GUI.
- Developed GUI for existing webservices of CRUD operations on User/Account.
- Feature designed to create user account that makes performs promise on results from Rest API.
- New functionality is designed along with backend APIs which will utilize the attributes based on which a user account is created.
- Migrated Angular 11 to 15 . Please find my questions and solution on Stack overflow → <u>Link</u>.
- Implemented Authentication and Authorization using flags that are set from groups obtained by Azure AD service.
- Exchange attributes value with Siblings components using services.
- Pass Values from Parent to Child component using @Input decorator on Variable in Typescript and using same as attribute inside child components selector tag which is set with OnChange LifeHook.
- <u>Azure AD</u> services implemented in <u>Improv Dashboard</u> and given training to <u>BrightSpeed</u>.
- Assisted in BrightSpeed <u>Divestiture</u> Project.

- Suggested changes in <u>ng-multiselect-dropdown</u> feature to developer to enhance it. Please us this Github <u>link</u> to view my contribution to enhance feature of dropdown.
- Created Pipeline to deploy Angular Dashboard to Kubernetes with Jenkins script whenever code is merged to a branch.

IMPROV Services:

- Development task JAVA 1.7 Spring Boot, Swagger template in YAML, DB
 MYSQL and LDAP
- Webservices to operate Modem Account services CRUD operations in Microservice architecture.
- Add new API to the hive, modifying Swagger file.
- Devising DSA that works neatly for processing data and generating readable loggers for support.
- Worked on adding more than one Database by using Transactional(name=) annotation of JPA.
- Responds to Requests over Kafka topics.
- Created Unit Test Cases using Mockito with mock and stubs. Version 5.x

Business Intelligence:

- Maintenance & Enhancements in HP-UX OS with Unix Script.
- PL/SQL jobs running reports for Crystal report.
- SQL Loader loading data to Oracle tables from flat files received from Remote sites.
- Crystal Report tool for developing reports for various Network planning information.
- Manage and update Cron jobs that trigger Daily, weekly, monthly and quarterly task. Also used these cron to send mail through Unix machine for reporting purpose.

Microbus:

- A middleware system builds on Apache ActiveMQ application.
- Master Slave architecture, secondary server becomes active whenever primary is unable to serve more requests.

Network Activation Platform (NAP):

- JAVA 1.3, Oracle SQL
- It's a legacy application that is utilized by many downstream applications to check the validity of point codes.

Inside Project

Technologies:

- Angular 9,11,15 and Typescript
- JAVA 7 in Spring Boot Framework
- Spring-Boot Version 2
- Swagger for API
- UNIX on HP-UNIX system
- Azure AD
- HTML templates
- UI Scripting by Nodejs and Angular
- MySQL
- GitHub Repo
- Jenkins Build Tool by webhooks
- Docker
- Deployment in Kubernetes Hands-On

Roles and Responsibilities:

- Improv Dashboard: Design and Development of new Dashboard in Angular 11.
- Integrated Angular Application with Pie chart and Line chart that is can be filtered with Time range with Datepicker.
- IMPROV Services: Added Multiple DB by utilizing Transactional annotation with name attribute.
- Create multi-tier Dockerfile for Angular application in CICD ecosystem that is triggered by Jenkins script when code pushed to Dev Branch.
- Suggesting Use Cases to onshore client and Manager.
- Understanding the Business and proposing the use cases according to that
- Peer Code review and brainstorming to achieve solutions.
- Tracking logs of Legacy applications.
- In case of issues in Legacy applications, root cause analysis and remedy Restart server, Contact DBA to get data into test DB.

Methodology:

- Follow Agile for Development task.
- For support, raises service now tickets to track.

Project#2	TATA Consultancy Services (1st Nov,2017- 28thNov,2019)	
Description of project	Walgreens 340b Program 340B project is governed by US government providing medicines to under privileged Uninsured users. Client Portal is a Client Facing application of 340B System, which is the only face of this program from where daily, weekly, monthly and manual reports are generated to check status of inventory and portfolio of all the Clinics associated with this program.	
Inside Project	 Technologies: Java 7 with Spring boot AngularJS Javascript JSP and Thymleaf HTML templates UI Scripting by AngularJs Gradle used for compiling the project. Stash is used as cloud SVN. Oracle Access Manager is used to maintain Access to this application (OAuth). Migrating to Ping Federation. Configuration Managements in Properties files, to maintain environment specific changes. 	
	 Roles and Responsibilities: Development Modules (DM) are released with functional changes and enhancements. Analyze business requirements to deliver changes as per expectation. Design Discussion and Design Document preparation Taking care of Database impact in each DM. Developing application using Spring framework. 	

•	Worked on JAVA based application used in Pharmacy system at
	Walgreens.
_	Written code for different modules as well as for generating PDE

- Written code for different modules as well as for generating PDF/XLS reports.
- Worked on JAVA based batches used in Walgreens.
- Working as JAVA/J2EE and SQL developer at Walgreens.
- Developed POJO classes to store and retrieve (DAO) data by the user.
- Developing presentation logic using JSP and Thymleaf HTML templates.
- Developed application presentation logic using JSP, HTML, CSS, and jQuery.
- Writing Unit test cases and prepared Unit test results.
- Bug Fixing during QA and UAT
 - ✓ Handled and actively resolved issues during QA deployment of Web application, batches.

Methodology:

 We work through agile Process to deliver DMs and maintain all the Documents which are validated at the time of Final Inspection of each DM.

Project #1	TATA Consultancy Services (1st Nov,2015-31st Oct,2017)		
Description of project	GE Capital Real Time Support: <u>GE's Leasing company</u> employee create deals for funding their end users(borrowers) by checking their credit health from different Bureaus like Germany's <u>Schufa</u> and UK's <u>Experian</u> also extended for <u>France</u> . Problems are faced during Deal creation that impacts business.		
Inside Project	Technologies: Java 7 with Spring MVC 2.x Oracle DB Message Queue JSP Javascript Ajax SOAP UI Maven build Tool Bitbucket		
	Roles and Responsibilities: Resolving issues of users in Real Time. Understanding the nature of issue and finding the root cause of it keeping user informed for the estimated time of resolving. Analysis extends: Data Base and Configuration Issues CR impacting the flow. Implemented Changes on spring framework-based web service. Extracted the web application related reports, requested by clients from Oracle database. Perform Sanity checks every day before Business hours to ensure proper		

Client from Germany, France, UK and other parts of Europe in whole.

functioning of application.

TRAININGS

In-House Training in TCS on Java Spring framework, PL/SQL Database and Agile process.

Achievements:

Award Name	Award Date	Award Category	Award SubCategory
Star of the Month Award	09-Aug-2019	Awards for Excellence	Star Awards
Service & Commitment Award	17-Aug-2018	Service Awards	Service Award
On The Spot Award	21-Nov-2017	Awards for Excellence	On The Spot Awards
On The Spot Award	29-Jun-2017	Awards for Excellence	On The Spot Awards
On The Spot Award	08-May-2017	Awards for Excellence	On The Spot Awards
On The Spot Award	07-Sep-2016	Awards for Excellence	On The Spot Awards
On The Spot Award	31-Aug-2016	Awards for Excellence	On The Spot Awards

Academic Credentials:

Degree	University	Institution	Percentage	Year
B.Sc.	CCS university	Meerut college	76.8	2013
12 th	C.B.S.E.	St. John's Sr. Sec. School	70	2010
10 th	C.B.S.E.	St. John's Sr. Sec. School	80	2008

Personal Attribute

Mother's Name	Seema Govind
Current Address	Chennai, Tamil Nadu
Permanent Address	107, Radha Kunj, Meerut, Uttar Pradesh 250002
DOB	5 June 1992
Hobbies	Running, Cycling, Swimming, Novels
Gender Marital Status	Male Married